Jiayee Lim

Software Engineer

me@jiayee.net | https://jiayee.net | https://github.com/jia1 | https://linkedin.com/in/jia1

SUMMARY

Experienced software engineer with 4+ years' background in full stack web development. Takes ownership of projects and is independent throughout the software development lifecycle. Achieves product and engineering goals by practising efficient project management. Passionate mentor and team player who propagates quality software and encourages collaboration.

SKILLS

Programming languages: Python, JavaScript, Java

Frameworks and libraries: React, Spring Boot

EXPERIENCE

Indeed, Singapore - Senior Software Engineer (Full-time)

JAN 2023 - MAR 2023

- Spearheaded reforms in the team's technical direction by championing frontend testing, defining
 effective testing methodology, and leading technical debt management with actionable steps.
- Led the project in reducing localisation inefficiencies by standardising requests through an in-house, self-service form creator written with React and Spring Boot.
- Nurtured junior engineers through mentorship.

Indeed, Singapore - Software Engineer (Full-time)

JUL 2019 - DEC 2022

- Single-handedly saved the company 180,000 USD/year by replacing outsourced manual labour with an
 error-resilient ETL pipeline written in Java.
- Reduced the time taken to localise products from months to days by streamlining translation workflows such as detecting untranslated texts in codebases and creating translation requests for them.
- Enabled marketing teams to set up campaigns autonomously through a self-service platform.
- Boosted employer engagement through personalisation of email marketing based on activity data.
- Accelerated product delivery by inspiring the team to prioritise code reviews. Shortened the code review cycle, which was mainly composed of waiting, from 7 to 2 days.
- Displayed technical leadership by guiding the team in: engineering solutions to vaguely-defined problems, managing stakeholders, planning work items, and establishing best practices in software delivery.
- Won the "Product, Technology and Engineering" award in the Indeed Singapore hackathon twice.

ViSenze, Singapore - Software Engineer (Intern, Part-time)

DEC 2018 - MAR 2019

- Guaranteed code correctness through tests in the image management platform. Unveiled bugs.
- Enhanced UX in the internal data platform through advanced form fields and form validation.

Visa, Singapore - Software Engineer (Intern)

MAY 2018 - JUL 2018

• Enabled configurable and programmatic performance testing by creating an Apache JMeter wrapper.

Visa, Singapore - Systems Engineer (Intern)

MAY 2017 - JUL 2017

- Eased access to virtual machine (VM) logs by delivering a configurable Chef client logger.
- Eliminated manual routines in IBM DataPower device deployment by implementing an Ansible module.

SPECIAL INTERESTS

Indeed, Singapore - Regional lead of Indeed Green Team (iGreen) APAC

JAN 2020 - MAR 2023

- Engaged a community of 110 members in APAC with sustainability news and calls to action.
- Led the coreteam of 4 with clear goals, strategies, OKRs on employee engagement, and action items.
- Organised iGreen Learn, a series of sustainability learning sessions. Maintained a strong engagement (30 people) without monetary incentives.
- Organised a hands-on composting workshop in the office, the first of its kind, and achieved a strong attendance and engagement (20 out of 45 people).

Indeed, Singapore - Indeed Brand Ambassador

SEP 2019 - MAR 2022

Represented Indeed at local university recruitment events and helped out at technical workshops.

Open Government Products, Singapore - Volunteer at FormSG

SEP 2020 - PRESENT

Volunteering with FormSG. Contributed to <u>17 issues</u>.

EDUCATION

National University of Singapore, Singapore - Bachelor of Computing (Honours) in Computer Science AUG 2015 - JUL 2019

AWARDS

- The Google Anita Borg Memorial Scholarship
- PwC Outstanding Award for Whole Leadership